how he swam across the river there,
как он короче там речку переплывал как
how he killed four fascists there,
он там короче четырёх фашистов завалил
in short, he himself has an award certificate. I looked
короче сам есть наградной лист Я смотрел
and you opened your mouth and said to me. What is it? It was
и Ты мне открываешь рот говоришь Это что
our grandfathers who fought; mine fought, but yours
Это наши деды воевали мой воевал А твой
didn’t fight;
не воевал твой сидел в плену всю войну
now
просидел Да работал на немцев А теперь
you're carrying it on a stick, such a hero, your grandfather
ты его на палке таскаешь такой герой дед
was Hello, where are you from,
был Привет ты откуда
from Russia? Well, I
из России откуда Ну
understand the towns. I'm originally from Rostov. But I've
городков понял Я сам родом из Ростова Но
been living in California for 18 years; in 2 years
18 лет живу в Калифорнии через 2 года
it will be  what kind of t-shirt do you have of the
будет дто что у тебя за
fatherland Well, I read what kind of t-
футболка отечества Ну я прочитал что за
shirt I don’t know so that you me
футболка Это не знаю так чтобы вы меня
it
это
then I just look like a Greek drakar
потом я просто смо греческий дракар
in short drawn And so that you can
короче нарисованный А чтоб напи
write who counts it Ned Cool and the
счит Кто никогда его Неда Прикольно а
Greek boat and this is no longer for me
греческий кораблик а это уже не ко мне
in Well you  you are wearing that Greek, not for me,
во Ну ты же носишь ты что грек не мне
I’m just there, I’m from a volunteer fund, and there
просто там я с волонтёрского фонда и там
we have, that is, such a
у нас то
tornado, so to speak. What kind of
есть вот такая вот так сказать смерч Что
volunteer are we
за волонт
sending parcels to the boys on s  And I understood,
отправляем посылки пацанам на с А понял
that is, in short, I
то есть Короче я
understood
понял
who Hitler Yugen in short Do you know who the
кто Гитлер юген короче А вы знаете кто
Nazis are? Yes, I know that they
такие нацисты Да знаю то которые
invade a foreign country, capture,
вторгаются в чужую страну захватывают
kill and support them,
убивают и поддерживают их
yes, the first test is available. Show me now, I’ll
да первый тест имеется Покажи сейчас
bring it, it’s just some kind of badge,
принесу так это просто значок какой-то а
namely the ribbon that you wear  Well, she’s
именно ленточка которую ты носишь ну она
present here, I can take it off, I’ll take it off
же тут присутствует я могу снять это я
myself. Well, take it off. Well, the ribbon is not for
его сам Ну сними Ну ленточка не для
badges because our grandfathers’ military
значков потому что диды наши вое
signs are the same Kato
знаками этоже Като
subculture is the word our grandfathers Yes My
субкультура это слово наши деды Да Мой
grandfather fought and yours  my great-grandfather fought,
дед воевал А твой воевал мой прадед
fought, Let's find it now, look, there is
воевал Давай сейчас найдём смотри есть
such a site, memory of the people. Here is my grandfather,
такой сайт память народа Вот мой дед
popk Andrei Vasilyevich, fought, there are
попк Андрей Васильевич воевал есть
awards oh popk Vasya Pavel Vasilyevich
наград ой попк Васи Павел Васильевич
Let us now hit your grandfather, let’s
Давай мы сейчас твоего деда
think he was with the Kans Nikolai Georgievich I
вроде был у канов Николай Георгиевич В
mean, it seems like he was You don’t remember
смысле вроде был Ты что не помнишь
your grandfather  I really don’t remember much. So
своего деда я прям сильно не помню Так
you have his awards. Come on, take him, this
ты у меня его награды Давай сес его вот
is a portrait of the Immortal
это портрет Бессмертный
Regiment  And you don’t remember your grandfather, yes. In general, it’s
полк А помнить деда не помнишь да Вообще
awesome that Nikolai Lukanov I remember that for sure,
офигенно что луканов Николай Это точно
I
помню я
Georgievich Well, I’m trying to test it
Георгиевич Ну вот пробе сечас пробиваю
now. Where is he from? In terms of the country, he’s not in any kind. In what region was he born because there will be a bunch of them there now? born also in
сейчас будет таких родился тоже в
Pskov in Pskov  region Let
Псковской в Псковской области Давай
's watch now
сейчас будем смотреть
So now we are like this
Так сейчас мы это так
[music]
[музыка]
PAMM What are you doing there yes this is a
ПАММ Что там у тебя делается да это
dog door
собака дверь
SKT because his name was Lukanov  Nikolay
СКТ так как его звали луканов Николай
Geo Lukanov
гео луканов
Yes
Да
Nikolay
Николай
Georgievich yes yes, you don’t remember the year of birth
Георгиевич да да год рождения не помнишь
Definitely
Точно
not, but he went through Two wars This is definitely after the
нет но он прошёл Две войны Это точно за
First and Second World Wars Now Now
первой и второй мирово Сейчас Сейчас
Let’s see, I didn’t find it, now we
посмотрим
’ll try again now, maybe if
попробуем сейчас вот может быть если
I think Now I’ll find it, I don’t remember where his
считаю Сейчас найду я не помню куда его
mother is  put it, come
мама положила
on, because you have to answer for your grandfather,
давай потому что за деда надо ответить
you said here Ours, yes Our grandfathers
ты тут сказал Наши да Вот наши деды
fought just And yours sat out
воевали как раз А ваши отсиживаться
for Hitler And by the way, I
за Гитлера были А вот это я кстати
condemn
осуждаю
this Well, he doesn’t find Lukanov
Так ну не находит не находит луканова
Nikolai now,
Николая сейчас
wait, show your grandfather on a stick, there is
ожидай показывай своего деда на палке
a whining dog.
собака скули
Come on, look for it so far, only
Давай ищи пока нашло только луканова
Nikolai Lukanov from the Moscow region, Klinsky
Николая из Московской области Клинский
district, is clearly found. He was definitely
район явно Это не по дцать первого года
not born in the first year of his life. He definitely couldn’t go through the First World War.
рождения точно не мог Первую мировую
Come on, look for his grandfather, so I’m looking for him
А давай ищи деда вот я его ищу
, my
ё-моё
only Lukanov  Nikolai Georgievich
единственный луканов Николай Георгиевич
is born in the twenty-first year from the
есть двадцать первого года рождения с
Moscow region. This is definitely not him; there is someone
Московской области Это точно не он кого
from the Moscow region;
с Московской области есть
here he is, Klinsky district Yes.  this one
вот он Клинский район Да этот
is
есть
so there is also Grigorievich from
так есть ещ Григорьевич из
Ryazan, also not
Рязанского тоже не
yours, in short, your grandfather was on the coast or are you
твой что-то короче дед прибрега или ты
lying fake grandfathers - this is the basis of
брешешь фейковые деды - это основа
Russia because everyone served in the Wehrmacht
России потому что служили все в вермахте
Yes, in the Vlasovites While our grandfathers fought,
Да Во власовцев Пока наши деды воевали
my grandfather you can look at the priest Pavel
моего деда можешь посмотреть попк Павел
Vasilyevich you can look when he was
Васильевич можешь посмотреть когда
called up  what awards Oh,
призван какие награды О даже наградной
there’s even an award list What feats he performed
лист есть Какие подвиги совершал
Well, in short, I don’t know, somewhere
Ну короче не знаю куда-то портрет Его
they put his portrait And where it is I don’t know anymore
положили А куда это мне уже неизвестно
Wait Stop  That is, you didn’t remember exactly your
Подожди Стоп То есть ты не помнил точно
grandfather, yes. Now you no longer have a portrait,
деда да Теперь у тебя уже нету портрета
that’s not it. Look, this is this, this is a
не это Это был Смотри это это это
betrayal of the fatherland; the memory of your
предательство отечества память предка
grandfather’s ancestor is lost; it’s just that if you had a
деда потерять это просто если у тебя был
grandfather and he’s lying around somewhere, maybe there’s
дед и он где-то валяется может него
a dog on him already. Let
собака на него уже Давай
me find him.  I’ll wait Well, this is real if you’re a
найди я подожду Ну это реально если ты
Rusich who [ __ ] honors his grandfathers Well, you
Русич который блин чтит своих дедов Ну
can’t wear a T-shirt like that if you have a
Такую футболку нельзя носить если у тебя
Grandfather lying in the trash heap somewhere.
Дед где-то блин на помойке валяется
Let me do it  I'll look,
Давай я поищу подожду
I'll wait, I
Поищи
'll try to find them for sure A O
попробую что те точно пом А О
found Yes Lukanov Nikolai
нашёл Да луканов Николай
Evi Opa found it before that you
еви Опа нашёл тобто до этого ты это
can't do it, but he still went through the First World War yes
никак а он Первую мировую ещё прошёл да
Cool, and the First World War In what year
Прикольно а первая мировая В каком году
did it start and what year
начались и в каком
did it end, honestly, I constantly confuse the
закончилась вот честно я постоянно путаю
dates you saw  your Grandfather was born in
даты ты видел у тебя Дед родился в
December of this year, when not only the First
декабре сего года когда не то что Первая
World Revolution had already passed,
Мировая уже революция прошла
but
ну
look, I don’t know much about this whole story
посмотри я вот за вот эту всю историю
yet because we do
пока что сильно не шарю потому что мы е
n’t
не
passed Show again the date of birth of
проходили Покажи ещ раз дату рождения
Grandfather there on December 25th or what
Деда там 25 декабря се или какого
year
года
Deka grandfather
Дека дед
was born Handsome but
родился Красава но в Первой Мировой
grandfather took part in the First World War Well done And show me
принял участие дед Молодец А покажи
When
Когда умер
grandfather died he died on May 29,
дед умер он 29 мая семдесят девятого
1979 And show me Show
года А покажи покажи
grandfather so look if he is
деда так вот смотри если он семьдесят
1979  yes If he had been a
девятого года да Если б он был
participant in the Great Patriotic War,
участником Великой Отечественной войны
for 20 years of Victory in the year sixty-five they
на 20 лет Победы в шестьдесят пятом году
gave
давали
uh orders and medals were distributed to everyone
ээ ордена и медали раздавали всем
veterans Yes, he is in the sixty-fifth
ветеранам Да есть он в шестьдесят пятом
year, he would have received it in the database even
году получил бы он бы в базе был даже
if he had nothing during the war,
если бы у него во время войны ничего не
yes he doesn’t have it, not that he doesn’t have any awards,
было да у него нету не то что наград нет
go there, there is a site in memory of the people,
такого вот зайти есть сайт память народа
now this is the Ministry of Defense of the
вот сейчас это Министерство обороны
Russian Federation in  ode and drive in
Российской Федерации в оде и вбей там
your grandfather there. Let's say it's called the memory of the
своего деда Дава сать называется память
people of my grandfather, drive in the priests Pavel
народа моего деда вбей попы Павел
Vasilyevich, you will find
Васильевич найдёшь
but your grandfather is not there,
а твоего деда нету
what is he now called the memory of the people,
как он сейчас называется память народа
something he doesn’t want to burden me with? Well,
что-то он меня грузить не хочет Ну
a little  he is dulling this site
немножко он подтупливает этот сайт
Because there are a lot of requests, everyone is looking for grandfathers,
Потому что много запросов все дедов ищут
I force everyone to find their grandfather.
я всех заставляю найти своего деда
Oh God, there
О Господи
is no such grandfather there. Lukanov la
там нету такого деда луканов ла
Georgievich found Yes, what year of birth is
Георгиевич нашл Да какого года рождения
1917, where is my first one?
1917 се где вот у меня первая так нет
So look at this, Ryazan this is not
Так посмотри это Рязанский это Это не
your grandfather, this is  from Ryazan grandfather no Yes, what does he
твой дед это из Рязани дед нет Да что
write there Ivanov region city of Vladimi
пишет Иванов область город владими
This is not this is not Pskov Truth is
Это не это не Псковская Правда
far away Well, let’s name where he was born, I
далеко Ну вот назначим где он родился я
don’t know because  Dad told me exactly
не знаю потому что мне папа именно
that he is the Pskov region,
говорил что он то есть Псковская область
yes And here you know where Pskovskaya is and
да А тут сжи ты знаешь где Псковская и
where
где
Ivanovskaya is. And
Ивановская А
sry now
sry сейчас подойду
I’ll come here, so now look at the one from the
я тут так теперь смотри тот который с
Ivanovo region Yes, that means the
Ивановской области Да вот он значит
seventeenth year, Furmanovsky military registration and enlistment office,
семнадцатый год фурмановский военкомат
Ivanovo region, city of Furmanov Yes, the
Ивановская область город Фурманов Да
date dropped out  departure on August 18,
выбыл дата выбытия 18 августа сорок
1941, reason for departure,
первого года причина выбытия попал в
captured in short, that is, if it were
плен короче То есть это если это был бы
your grandfather, he was in August, that is, literally  the
твой дед он в августе то есть буквально
month the war started is not even the month of
месяц начала войны даже не месяц
June 22 for a month and a half of the war and
какого 22 июня на полтора месяца войны и
he surrendered to the Germans and spent the entire
он сдался в плен немцев и просидел всю
war in
войну в
captivity. Dude, this is definitely your grandfather. I don’t know,
плену Чувак это точно твой дед Я не знаю
ask your dad or he’s from the Ivanovo
спроси у папы или он с Ивановской
region. It’s even more interesting if
области это Даже интереснее если чем
I don’t have a grandfather.  dad is at war, well,
деда нет У меня папа на войне так Ну
call either mom or dad, call and ask,
позвони или маме или папе позвони спроси
maybe dad will also be in captivity like the grandfather of
может папа тоже в плену будет как дед
no one
некого
for a month, damn
нечаевы меся
it, our Soviet citizen surrendered in the
сдался блин Советский наш гражданин в
first months  war with weapons,
первые месяцы войны с оружием сдался
in short, he surrendered to the Germans, well, look there. Click on
короче немцам ну посмотри там Нажми на
this guy from the Ivanovo region and tell him to
этого ше с Ивановской области и скажи
renounce this grandfather, that this is no longer
отрекается от этого деда что это уже не
your grandfather. Well, there were no others in the forty-first
твой дед Ну других нен в соро первом
year. Well, he was released from captivity in the forty-first
году Ну из плена освобождён в соро перво
year. No, this is the date of departure, the date is written there
году Нет это дата выбытия там написано
retirement
дата выбытия
18084 reason was captured And released
18084 причина попал в плен А освобождён
means that he was later released
это что он потом освобождён уже
When the war ended, I don’t
Когда война закончилась вобще нифига не
understand anything  you carry on a stick a grandfather who
понимаю таскаешь на палке деда который
surrendered to the Germans with a
немцам сдался в плен с
weapon and spent time in the
оружием и просидел
Armed Forces, the very memory that but again he was
ВС сама память что но опять же он был
released from captivity, they
освобождён с плена
fought and shed blood, he stupidly
воевали Да проливали кровь он тупо
surrendered so as not to fight, he did not
сдался в плен чтобы не воевать он не
fight until the last cartridge and then did not
воевал до последнего патрона а потом не
go with a bayonet knife  at the German and didn’t choke
шёл со штык ножом на немца и не душил
him Yes, he told him they told him Hyundai hoch
его Да он сказал ему сказали хенде хох
he’s like hurray hurray you can
он такой ура ура можно
now eat German butter  German
теперь немецкое масло кушать немецкий
bread and sat, what he did was digging trenches for the
хлеб и сидел что он делал копал траншеи
Germans. Yes, because it was not just in
немцам Да потому что это же не просто в
captivity that he worked against our
плену он работал да против нашей
Soviet Army, that is, for 4 years
Советской Армии то есть 4 года
according to the Soviet Union,
по со п
but no one knows this anymore. Well, just as
да это уже никому не известно Ну как
no one knows all the Soviet prisoners of war from the
никому неизвестно все военнопленные с
forty-first year  Yes, they worked
сорок первого года советские Да работали
for Hitler’s Germany, built
на гитлеровскую Германию строили
fortified areas and so on. And then
укрепрайоны и так дальше Да потом
who My grandfather then went to shoot at those
который Мой дед потом Шёл на пули на те
fortified areas that your grandfather dug,
укреп районы которые твой дед копал
you know, your grandfather And my grandfather here
понимаешь твой дед А мой дед вот
look at the priest Pavel Vasilyevich, everything
посмотри попк Павел Васильевич там всё
is there, how he swam across the river there,
есть как он короче там речку переплывал
how he killed four fascists there,
как он там короче четырёх фашистов
in short, he himself has an award sheet. I
завалил короче сам есть наградной лист Я
looked and you opened your mouth and said to me. What is it? It was
смотрел и Ты мне открываешь рот говоришь
our grandfathers who fought, mine fought,
Это что Это наши деды воевали мой воевал
but yours didn’t fight, yours was in captivity all the time  He
А твой не воевал твой сидел в плену всю
sat through the war Yes, he worked for the Germans And
войну просидел Да работал на немцев А
now you are carrying him on a stick, such a
теперь ты его на палке таскаешь такой
hero, your grandfather was, yes, and we are sure that this is
герой дед был да а мым уверены что это
straight My grandfather, you And that is, you are already
пря Мой дед ты А то есть ты уже
renouncing  from this grandfather from Ivanovskaya
отрекается от этого деда из Ивановской
Well, look, come on Nikolai Georgievich Lukanov,
Ну смотри давай луканов Николай
born in 1917, as you said, as
1917 года рождения как ты сказал как там
shown there Well, it’s not Pskov Ivanovskaya
показано ж Да вот не псковско ивановска
you said, maybe that is, now you are already
ты сказал может то есть теперь ты уже
shorter de That is, it turns out, look, if
короче де То есть получается смотри если
this is not your grandfather, then your grandfather is not at all
это не твой дед тогда твой дед вообще не
fought Because he is not in the database, the
воевал Потому что его нет в базе тут нет
only one
единственный луканов Николай Георгиевич
who is in the database is Nikolai Georgievich Lukanov, this is all the
который есть в базе это вот это все
Red Army servicemen who are on
военнослужащие Красной Армии есть на
this site is the site of the archive of the Ministry of
этом сайте это сайт архива Министерства
Defense which all digitized Soviet documents
обороны который все советские документы
are entered into the database, everyone Even
оцифрованные забиты в базу каждый Даже
the one who was in the war for one day is in
тот кто был на войне один день есть во
all these orders And so on, either
всех этих приказах И так дальше либо
your grandfather, if you say this is not your
твой дед если ты говоришь это не твой
grandfather, it means he didn’t fight, it’s a fake Grandfather
дед значит он не воевал это фейковый Дед
served time  somewhere on the wane Or maybe he was
отсидел со где-то на чах А может был
even under German occupation and worked as a policeman
даже под немецкой оккупацией и полицаем
and it could be like this, he’s so
и такое может быть как это он так
grown up and didn’t fight, but if he fought
взрослый и не воевал то а если воевал
then this grandfather is a traitor  who
тогда вот это этот дед предатель который
surrendered to the Nazis in the first
сдался в первых
months,
месяцах
no, I just looked. It’s
нацистам не вот я просто смот Тут даже
not even written here, that is, he was released from
не написано что то есть был освобождён с
forty-fifth, so
сорок пятого потому ещё раз так вот
look again when the Germans were
смотри когда немцев немцы которые
taken prisoner by the Germans. Yes, they were taken to the rear, they
забирали в плен Да их отвозили в тыл они
worked; you can’t free a person from
работали нельзя освободить человека из
captivity. No.  having captured the Germans, Germany had already
плена Да не захватив немцев уже Германию
released all the prisoners like in
всех пленных типа освободили в сорок
'45. Uh-huh. Well, he didn't fight anymore, that
пятом Угу Ну и Больше он не воевал то
is, look. Because if he had
есть смотри Потому что если бы его
been released in '43, he would have stood
освободили в сорок третьем он бы встал
on  registered in 1943 and would have gone to
на учёт в сорок третьем и пошёл бы
fight in 1943, it’s
воевать в сорок третьем
true But that’s where he dropped out. You
правда А так вот там всё выбыл Ты же
read he dropped out. In 1941 he surrendered as a
прочитал выбыл В сорок первом сдался в
prisoner on
плен 8
August 8, a disgrace to the family. It’s just terrible. If
августа позор семьи Это просто ужас Если
I had a grandfather like that, I would be embarrassed to
бы у меня такой Дед был я бы стеснялся
even say that my grandfather
вообще говорить что дед
fought  there on August 18, the tree-sticks
воевал вона 18 августа ёлки-палки
didn’t even last 4 days to fight for 2 months,
даже 4 дня не дотянул чтобы 2 месяца
the freak is
повоевать урода
just
просто
tinny, look there You can even
жесть там посмотри Ты даже можешь
open it, there’s this sheet there, it’s
открыть там есть вот этот лист там
even painted there  so
расписано даже вот так
that’s why there were no awards
так и поэтому никаких наград не было
because he surrendered and served time in captivity.
потому что в плен сдался отсидел в
And our Ukrainian grandfathers
плену А наши украинские деды
shed their blood. If you want to talk about Ukraine in general,
проливали м пер хотите скать вообще про
I want to say that you opened
Украину Я хочу сказать что ты открыл
your mouth and said when I said that we,
свой рот и сказал когда я сказал что мы
our grandfathers, fought  But you are still ours And so I
наши деды воевали А ты таки наши И так
continued to doubt my grandfather But
дальше усомнился в моём деде А вот
really, ours didn’t fight, mine
действительно наши не воевали мои
fought, yours didn’t fight if it
воевали твой не воевал если у тебя это
was your great-grandfather you say Yes, you want to
был твой прадед ты говоришь Да вы хотите
say that  your one grandfather won yet This is
сказать что ваш один дед победил ещ Это
if you said great-grandfather Yes, this is one
если ты прадеда сказал Да это один
great-grandfather and great-grandfathers You have four, in fact,
прадед да прадедов У тебя четыре по сути
out of four, one of them at least fought,
из четырёх кто-то один хотя бы воевал я
I don’t know. I mean, they talked about one of them. Why didn’t they talk about the Three? I don’t know
А почему про Трёх не говорили я не знаю
about them  in general
о них вообще
Yeah, that is, none of the four great-
Ага то есть из четырёх
grandfathers fought. And I know. Well, how can you
прадедов никто не воевал А я знаю Ну как
not know about your great-grandfathers? For
это не знать про своих прадедов Я
example, I know my grandfathers and great-grandfathers, so I
например дедов и прадедов знаю так я
asked my parents, my grandmother,
спрашивал у родителей у бабушки
and what they
спрашивал и что они
they said they don’t know themselves the meaning of they don’t know
говорили не знают сами смысле не знают
how they don’t know whether children fought or not or
как не знают воевал дет или не либо
killed that something is either missing
убитые что что либо в безвести пропавшие
or killed, well wait Well, they know whether my
либо убитые ну подожди Ну они знают
great-grandfather fought or didn’t
воевал прадед или не
fight, that is, well, I asked them this
воевал то есть ну я у них это спрашивал
about me, they didn’t
о мне не
talk about this  and it’s funny how
говорили в этом-то и прикол а как это
funny they didn’t say If he fought, it means
прикол не говорили Если он воевал значит
he was a hero, yes they talk about it, they
герой он был да об этом говорят
show him on a stick,
показывают на палку его
how is it that out of four
натягивает как это из четырёх
grandfathers they don’t talk about three, either he fought
дедов про трих не говорят или он воевал
or didn’t fight alone  hanged on a stick and
или не воевал одного повесили на палку и
then the captive surrendered to the
то плен сдался фашистом
Nazi fascist. It's just a
нацистом Это просто
shame. That is, you at least remember
позор То есть получается ты хоть помнишь
the names of these grandfathers and
фамилии этих дедов
great-grandfathers. How do I know them if I've
прадедов Откуда мне их знать если я их
never even heard of them? Where did you come from? How did
даже ни разу о них не слышал Откуда Как
you not hear about your great-grandfathers?
ты не слышал о своих прадедах Ну вот так
for example, I may not have heard about my great-grandfathers yet,
вот ну я напри Я про прадедов ещё может
yes, but I have heard of my great-grandfathers, I even
не слышал Да но прадедов слышал Даже
saw photographs, I even know what they
фотографии видел даже знаю как они
are called because I asked my grandmother, I
зовутся потому что у бабушки спрашивал у
asked my grandfather  Dad, he knew his
дедушки спрашивал у папы он знал своих
grandfathers. You have TET knows his grandfathers,
дедов У тебя же ТЕТ знает своих дедов
they are your great-grandfathers, he knows. So
они же твои прадеды он-то знает Так
why doesn’t he say he had one
почему не говорит у него был один
grandfather, he’s like reproducing by budding,
дед он типа почкованием
like Two grandfathers should be
размножаться то как Два деда должно быть
like two, like Two grandfathers, it should be
как два как Два деда должно быть это
clear, but  wait and explain to you
понятно но подожди ещё тебе объяснить
how look how in normal families it
как смотри как в нормальных семьях
turns out Two grandfathers So you have
получается Два деда Значит у тебя есть
a father and a mother, a father has a father and a mother, and
папа и мама у папы есть папа и мама и
then there is a father and a mother, a father, a mother and his wives
тут папа и мама папа мама и его жены ещё
also a father, a mother, yes, that is, there are Two  grandfather
тоже папа мама да то есть есть Два деда
and four great-grandfathers, here’s the second and about
и четыре прадеда вот второго и про
the third and the fourth, I have
третьего и про четвёртого я вообще
n’t heard anything at all. Why And I know
ничего не слышал А почему А я знаю
Well, look, you’re such a Patriot, the son of the
Ну как Смотри ты такой Патриот сын
fatherland, your father. The Patriot, the son of the
отечества твой батя Патриот сын
fatherland, went to fight a foreign country. Yes, but
отечества пошл воевать чужую страну Да а
he doesn’t know, or whether his grandfathers fought and didn’t
он не знает или воевали его деды и не
tells you
говорит тебе
this is what you just
вот чему вы сейчас это
said, yes, because the previous dads
сказали да потому что предыдущие бати
who went to Ukraine, they and yours, it’s really a matter of
которые пошли в Украину они и тво вопрос
time,
времени
look, we’ll leave Victory
реально смотри уйдём с Победы вот
let’s say I don’t know how you’ll find me, that’s what you’ll tell me then, you’ll leave victorious, dude, please let your share of the USA tell your dad to win, that you must capture Kyiv, capture Washington, what you must do, that you won, we need Ukraine to stop resisting You must capture Kyiv Lvov London that it will be necessary at least they will capture Ukraine if they have to, dude you were already standing near Kiev stupid politician ordered you to go back you Putin  you called the thick-headed
идти ты Путина назвал тупоголовый
know of the PPP you just named the Supreme
зна ППП ты сейчас назвал верховного
Commander-in-Chief who refused the
главнокомандующего который дал отказ
order to leave Kiev you called the thick-headed
приказ уйти от Киева назвал тупоголовый
you're the first damn guy You really are the son of the
ты первый блин пацан Ты реально ты сын
fatherland You're the first man who is not
отечества Ты первый мужчина который не
Putin and said that he's dumb-headed yes
Путина и сказал что он тупоголовый да
so And what's so no, that is, you don't agree
так А что так нет то есть Вы не согласны
with  because that is, it’s stupid to take it away from the
с тем что то есть это тупо отвести от
borders, wait a hundred That is, you now
границ подожди сто То есть ты сейчас
think that your dad is
считаешь что твой папа за
n’t dying for a stupid moment. He’s on
тупоголовый момент не умирает Он в
vacation. He’s currently  That
отпуске На данный момент находится То
is, your dad is fighting for
есть твой папа воюет за
the stupid people Who are they, that is, they are fighting
тупоголовые Кто есть они то есть воюют
for the stupid people and Zelensky Who is he there
за тупоголовый и Зеленского Кто он там
and because of stupid Putin and something like that
да изза тупого Путина да типа того
Wait for your dad mobile phone Zro
Подожди у тебя папа мобили Зро
contract
контрактовый
sent your dad to fight in the second
твоего папу отправил воевать в втором
year of the campaign yes yes, that is, your dad is already
году походу да да то есть твой папа уже
more  d years not just will be 2 years
больше д лет не как раз будет 2 года Вот
This is now Yes not already yes 2 years 2
это сейчас Да не уже есть да 2 года 2
years has come more than two years he has been fighting Because
года пришло больше дву лет воюет Потому
he was sent there by the stupid
что его послал туда тупоголовый
Putin not  Well, I mean now at
Путин не Ну я имею в виду сейчас на
the moment about that, that is, Okay, if
данный момент про то то есть Ладно если
he’s already doing something else there, but
он там другое уже чтото делает а вот
precisely that that is, he’s withdrawing troops
именно то что то есть он отводит войска
from the borders
от границ
What’s
Что
funny, wait again, I
смешного подожди ещё раз я правильно
understand correctly, wrong, wait, well, you yourself
понимаю неправильно подожди ну ты Ты сам
said that Putin
сказал что Путин
stupid turns out to be stupid Putin
тупоголовый получается тупоголовый Путин
took your
взял твоего
dad,
папу
threw him into the
бросил на
war And now your dad is fighting for stupid
войну И сейчас твой папа воюет за тупого
Putin for his ideas Yes, I’m saying for that
Путина за его идеи Да я говорю за то
What in one
Что за один
case is good, but
случай хорошо а с Харьковской области
stupid Putin also gave the
убежать тупоголовый Путин тоже дал
order to escape from the Kharkov region, or  without an order
приказ или без приказа
you fled from Kharkov Yes, so now in
убежали с Харьковской Да так сейчас на
Kharkov raisin Kupyansk You were
Харькове изюм Купянск Вы же были
occupied part of the Kharkov region and
оккупировали часть Харьковской обла а
then you were thrown out of there you ran away in a
потом вас выкинули оттуда вы убежали за
day at the moment we are in
день на данный момент мы находимся в
Kharkov what Kharkov are you in
Харькове в каком Харькове ты находишься
baby
малыш
don’t look again in the second year you
не ещё раз смотри в д втором году вас
expelled from the Kharkov region, it was Putin who
выгнали из Харьковской области это Путин
gave the order to escape from the raisins of
дал приказ убежать из изюма
Kupyansk, so it was an order, a thick-headed
купянска так Это был приказ тупоголовый
order  Putin turns out yes What is this about
приказ Путина получается да Что вот это
transporting troops that have
вот отвозить войска которые захвачены
already captured territory but this is really stupid Well,
уже территорию но это реально тупо Ну
that’s right, that is, half yes, that
правильно то есть то есть полу да то
is, look Putin once gave a stupid
есть смотри Путин один раз дал тупой
order to escape from Kiev, the second time he
приказ убежать из-под Киева второй раз
gave a stupid order to escape from the Kharkov
дал тупой приказ убежать из Харьковской
region and attention  the city of Kherson, which
области и внимание город Херсон который
seems to have been included in the Russian Federation,
вроде вписали в Российскую Федерацию
held a referendum there and someone, the
провели там референдум и кто-то
Supreme
Верховный
Commander-in-Chief Vladimir Putin,
главнокомандующий Владимир Путин
stupid, gave the order to leave Kherson
тупоголовый дал приказ уйти из Херсона
like this And I already know this  politics that is,
так А я знаю это уже политика то есть
look, if Putin once stupid gave the
смотри если Путин раз тупоголовый дал
order to run away second third Don’t you
приказ убежать второй третий Тебе не
think that this is not an accident but
кажется что это не Случайность а
stupid systemicity
тупоголовая системность
most of all in Zelensky Well look
больше всего у Зеленского Ну смотри
Wait again look I’m not saying
Подожди ещё раз смотри я же не говорю
Zelensky you’re in Russia your dad sent
Зеленский ты в России твой папа пошл
your dad Putin took him to fight in
твоего папу взял Путин воевать в
In Ukraine, stupid Putin put a
Украине ту Путин тупоголовый положил под
huge number of your guys near Kiev and
Киевом огромное количество ваших ребят и
gave them the order to
дал им приказ
run away in the Kharkov region, put
убежать в Харьковской области положил
a bunch of guys and gave them the order to run away to
кучу ребят и дал им приказ убежать в
Kherson put a bunch of guys and gave them a
Херсоне положил кучу ребят и дал им
prison sentence, so that’s what I’m telling you about, that
прика ужа вот Я вот про это вам и говорю
is, these stupid orders,
что то есть вот эти вот тупые приказы
that is, captured territories and
что то есть захваченные территории и с
run away from them. More precisely, that is, they give an order
них убегать Точнее то есть дают приказ
like back, right, then the question is the question
типа назад правильно то вопрос вопрос
Why is your dad you and  all the sons of the fatherland
Почему твой папа ты и все сыны отечества
don’t ask Putin a question. Why is this
не задают Путину вопрос А нафига это
all for nothing? Why are they leaving us to die in
вообще всё Зачем нас бросают умереть в
Ukraine and then they were indignant about it and
Украине а потом об этом возмущалась а
then give the order to run away?
потом дать приказ убежать
So the whole country was indignant about it,
так вся страна об этом возмущалась
yes And how indignant you were you  went to
да И как ты возмутился ты вышел На
some kind of rally, how the country was indignant, I
митинг какой-то как возмущалась
don’t know, they even wrote some letters to
страна не знаю там даже некоторые письма
Putin, and letter O is the pinnacle of
Путину писали а пись О это вершина
indignation Write a letter And they
возмущения Написать письмо А индивиду
wrote individual or
письма индивидуальные писали или
collective letters to an individual And I know, well, because an
коллективные А я знаю ну потому что
individual letter is a small
индивидуальное письмо - это маленькая
form of indignation when
форма возмущения когда сильно
people are very indignant. It is necessary  sign
возмущается народ Нужно подписать там
a letter there from the plant staff, for example from the
письмо от коллектива завода например от
school staff,
коллектива школы
this is no longer a question for me.
это уже больше не ко мне вопрос Может
Maybe it’s interesting there children, grandchildren, wives,
может интересно там дети внуки жёны
maybe all these mobile phones Zro went to a
может этих всех мобили Зро вышли на
rally and asked Putin What kind of
митинг и спросили Путин Что за
[ __ ]  like How Come on, because
фигня как Как Давай так как возмущалась
besides the letters the whole country and the telegram were indignant. And I
кроме писем вся страна и телеграма А я
know you said that she was indignant,
знаю ты сказал что она возмущалась
how do you know that there was indignation at
откуда ты знаешь что было возмущение
Vinto, it seems like there was even one,
винто вроде бы один даже был
probably, or it was about another rally, I do
наверно либо это про другое митинг был я
n’t know for sure. Now look, it’s very
уже точно не знаю А теперь смотри очень
complicated now  there will be
сложный сейчас будет
a question why the thick-headed Putin gave the
вопрос почему тупоголовый Путин дал
order to withdraw from the Kursk region from the
приказ отойти из Курской области с
Kursk region they threw the border and allowed
Курской области кинули границу и Дали
NATO troops led by
войскам НАТО под предводительством
Ukraine to capture the Kursk region I
Украины захватить курскую область вообще
don’t know anything at all, I don’t taste  I don’t even climb
почти ничего не знаю вкус я не лезу даже
And why don’t you climb about me I don’t even
А что не лезешь о м я даже ничего не
read anything And that you don’t
читаю А что не
read that is, this is
читаешь то есть это уже
more so to
больше так
say how to formulate
сказать как сформулировать
Formulate this is more a mistake of the head of the
Сформулируй это уже больше ошибка главы
Ministry of Defense for making such a
Министерства обороны что допусти такую
mistake PPP e times the head of the Ministry of
ошибку ППП е раз главы Министерства
Defense
оборо
Supreme Commander-in-Chief Vladimir
Верховный главнокомандующий Владимир
Putin is not taking off  he is responsible for the
Путин не снима с него ответственности на
Ministry of Defense of the Rhone And so on
Министерство обороны Роны И так дальше
Yes, he is responsible for everything, he is the Supreme
Да он отвечает за всё он Верховный
Commander-in-Chief, the
главнокомандующий
Supreme Commander, I know nothing I am into politics
верховный знаю ничего Я в политику
op Look you  you know something about the
оп Смотри ты что-то знаешь про
Kharkov region
харьковскую область
xn
хн
this is not politics this is your country
во это не политика это твоя страна
Kursk region This is your country
Курская область Это твоя страна
stop stop you stop you are the son of the fatherland you are
стоп стоп ты стоп ты сын отечества на
wearing a T-shirt Read again what
тебе футболка Прочитай ещё что раз там
was written there Well, I’m Neda, read what is
написано было Ну я же Неда прочитай что
written there I already read that son  who
там написано Я уже читал тот сын который
will sell like the fatherland Yes Fatherland Well, I’m
продаст типа отчизну Да Отечество Ну я
not betraying you are passing on you are passing on
же не предаю передаёшь передаёшь потому
because silence when when the sons of the fatherland
что молчание когда когда сыны отечества
see that the Fatherland is being trampled upon by comrade
видят что Отечество стаптывается товари
Stalin for this  shot if you
Сталин за такое расстреливал если ты
watched a platoon of German soldiers Yes
смотрел как взвод немецких солдат Да
destroy a village and was silent
уничтожает село и молчал
execution if you saw how the Nazis
расстрел если ты видел как нацисты
Yes
Да живьём
women
женщин
old men
стариков
shot alive if you yes this was banter if
расстрел если ты да это стёб был ес если
you served in captivity since the first year Like
ты отсидел с со перго года в плену Как
your grandfather Yes execution why he was
твой дед Да расстрел почему его
pardoned bribe taker probably  there was also a
помиловали взяточника наверно ещ был
bribe taker, so look at the Kurdish
взяточник так вот смотри курдская
region, you are not politicians, not politicians,
область ты сразу не политики не политики
you are collecting something there, some kind of
ты ж там что-то собираешь какие-то
humanitarian  help is not me
гуманитарную помощь не я собираю
collecting, collecting the president of the headquarters That is, he
собирают президент штаба То есть он
places And what are you doing? What are you
размещает А ты что делаешь Ты что
doing? I’m helping to load, I’m walking around the slab of the
делаешь Я помогаю загружать хожу плиту
network That’s why you don’t ask
сети Вот вот почему ты не спросишь
Listen, why do I weave networks and where
Слушайте а почему я плету сети а где вот
look, Russia is the country in which there is
смотри Россия страна в которой есть
oil gas gold diamonds the richest
нефть газ золото алмазы богатейшая
country of the world
страна мира
true question Why in Russia they can’t
правда вопрос Почему в России не могут
make millions of these networks at some factory
на каком-то заводе сделать миллионы этих
Why should people like you go around
сетей Почему такие как ты должны ходить
and weave something who takes all the
и что-то там плести кто забирает все
money from oil gas diamonds And I
деньги от нефти газа алмазов А я
know That is, I’m right  I understand
знаю То есть я правильно понимаю
Nega gold diamonds Putin and his pack
Нега золото алмазы Путин и его свора
take it for themselves buy yachts airplanes
забирают это себе покупают яхты самолёты
chicks and your dad is sent to die
тёлочек а твоего папу отправляют умереть
in Ukraine And you are sent to weave
в Украину А тебя отправляют плести
nets, not me alone, there are already a lot of them there
сетки не меня одного там уже идт много
Dato voluntarily
Дато добровольно
that you are collecting humanitarian aid
что вы собираете гуманитарку
that These cars are like
что Машины эти как
their motorcycles and for four  question question
их мотоциклы и на четыр вопрос вопрос А
Why can’t this look here you are at
почему это не может смотри вот вы вы
war with Ukraine Ukraine is a small
воюете с украино Украина - это маленькое
state without oil gas gold
государство без нефти газа золото
diamonds Why Russia which has oil
алмазов Почему Россия у которой нефть
gas  he can’t buy gold diamonds for the
газ золото алмазы не может купить на
front;
фронт
cars are no longer a question for me. So
машины это уже не ко мне вопро Так
why am I collecting for you
почему я к тебе собира
and won’t you say Hey state? Where are
во и не скажете Эй государство А где
the cars for the
машины на
front? this again is not a question for me; I’m not the
фронт это опять же не ко мне вопрос не Я
president of the headquarters; why don’t you
президент штаба не А почему ты не
tell the president of the headquarters?  Listen, why are
скажешь президенту штаба Слушай а почему
we here collecting for a car? Yes, but
мы вот тут собираем на машину Да а у
all these ministers have
шагу у всех этих министров у Путина
shorter palaces, yachts, steamships, and Putin has shorter palaces. Why
короче дворцы яхты пароходы Почему
don’t I know all this? Why am I even going? Why are
не лезу А почему собираюсь даже А почему
n’t you going? It’s not necessary  this is
не собираешься нем это не надо это же
your
твои
money, which is mine, I don’t have any
деньги Какие мои У меня нету
pocket money,
денег в плане
look again, oil gas,
карманных ещё раз смотри нефть газ
gold, diamonds, this is all the property of the people of the
золото алмаза это ж всё достояние народа
Russian Federation, this is your money, yours, your father,
Российской Федерации Это ваши деньги
who is
твои твоего бати который скоро
coming soon And you
дальше И ты
say
говориш е
you have very good jokes,
у вас шутки прямо очень
not why, but by the way  how much
а не почему а кстати сколько сейчас
do they now pay for the dead in Russia? 3.5
выплачивают за погибшего в России 3,5
million And what can you buy with these 3.5 million? Well,
млн А что можно купить на эти 3,5 млн Ну
I’m not familiar with Russian prices; I
я не не ориентируюсь в русских ценах уже
don’t know for a long time, you can buy something, but I’m
давно не знаю можно что-то купить но я
at the prices of Well  this is 35,000 dollars,
по ценам на Ну это это 35.000 долларов
it turns out I don’t know how much a dollar is now
получается не знаю сколько сейчас доллар
I don’t know Well, 100 dollar 100 I divide by
Я не знаю Ну 100 доллар 100 я делю на
100 it turns out to be 35,000 dollars I
100 это получается 35.000 долларов Мне
need it, but why the hell do I need this
нужен а вот нафиг он мне нужен этот
dollar, no, no, I’ll just make sure I
доллар нене так я я вот смотри чтобы я
understand because I’m an American Yes  I’m
понял потому что я же американец Да мне
wondering, I can’t buy it in dollars for 35,000
интересно я в долларах за 35.000
dollars even in your city.
долларов даже в твоём городе не купишь
What city are you from and Pskov? Well, you’re not
Ты из какого города а Псков Ну ты в
even in Pskov  you can’t buy it for 35 For
Пскове квартиру даже не купишь за 35 За
3.5
3,5
million or you’ll
млн или убитую какую-то
buy a dead one, that is, you wo
купишь то есть получа
n’t get the dawn Well, I mean, look, it
зари не Ну я имею в виду что смотри
turns out that you can buy for 3 C5 ml
получается что можно купить за 3 С5 мл
How much does it cost you, for example, Lada Vesta
Сколько стоит у Вас например Лада Веста
is now new
сейчас новая
Da mi 200 that is, at  it’s possible to buy
Да ми 200 то есть на это можно купить
three Lada
три Лады
Vst,
вст
approximately the state sent my dad to the
примерно государство папу отправила на
war And for his death I’m ready to pay
войну И за его смерть готова выплатить
three Lada
три Лады
Vest, not okay,
Вест не ладно
but how many of you are there in the family,
вот а вас сколько в семье
by the way,
кстати
four mother and three sons or three
четверо мама и трое сыновей или трое
daughters who is Mom I  brother
дочерей кто Мама я брат
dad that is, without dad there are three of you mom Yes
папа то есть без папы вас трое мама Да
brother and you that is just three cars
брат и ты то есть как раз три машины
cool
прикольно
one we
одна у нас
have what kind of car do you have
есть какая есть у вас
with your mom yes yes so good 1 200
машина у мамы да да так хорошо 1 200
you have a car mi 200 brother still has 900
тебе тачку ми 200 брату ещё остаётся 900
900000 rubles 9
900000 руб 9
dollars  small thing, you can
долларов по мелочёвка можно ремонтик
do some repairs there in the room.
сделать-то там в комнате
Cool. And what you're carrying is also
Прикольно А ты неся вотже
interesting, that thick-headed one
интересно тот который тупоголовый
who throws your guys to die
который там бросает ваших ребят умирать
in Ukraine and then withdraws the troops  Why does
в Украину а потом отводит войска Почему
n’t anyone ask Him a question? You won’t ask
Ему никто не задаст вопрос Ты не задашь
a question Why don’t Peskov’s
вопрос Да почему не воюют дети Пескова
children, Medvedev’s children, Putin’s children fight? Why don’t
дети Медведева дети Путина Почему не
the children of anyone from the Russian
воюют дети никого из российской
nobility fight? Why did Stalin’s son
знати Почему у Сталина сын
fight? And none of them fight,
воевал А у всех них не воюет
I don’t know at all, even if Putin has
я вообще не знаю даже если Путину у
a son or  anyone Well, in general,
Путина сын или кто-нибудь Ну вообще
look at least Putin Volodin Medvedev there
смотри хоть Путин Володин Медведев там
Lavrov and so on Shaigumarov
Лавров и так дальше шайгумаров
these are questions for them so for them so
это вот уже к ним вопросы так к ним так
Why don’t you  you ask them questions Why have
Почему ты не задаёшь им вопросы Почему
you been without a father for 2 years, yes, but they started
ты без отца 2 года да а они затеяли
a war themselves, they don’t go to it, and you have been without a father for
войну сами на неё не идут а ты без отца
years, the question is not for me, again, I can
года не ко мне вопрос опять же я Я могу
ask them this question How do
им задать этот вопрос Каким образом
you write a letter, I can, and I can write a letter
напишешь письмо могу е написать письмо
even this way  write I don’t know, I
даже и так могу написать Не знаю даже на
can even call Putin’s hotline Do
горячую ледени Путина могу позвонить
you have the number of
У тебя есть номер горячей линии
Putin’s hotline, did you call
Путина ты звонил на
it Yes, and what did you say, didn’t say that
неё Да и что говорил не говорил что
why what
почему что
else was it at the beginning of this year
го это ещё было в начале этого года Ну
Well, what did you say on the
ну что ты сказал на
hotline remember  vovo
горячий помни вово
Tell me your question and what did you tell her and
Скажите свой вопрос и ты что сказал ей а
I
я
know you didn’t you didn’t ask a question about your
знаю ты не ты не задал вопрос про своего
dad anything Yes I didn’t
папу ничего Да не
ask I don’t remember at all what I
задал я не помню вообще что я у него
asked him what I told her Why did you
спросил что я ей сказал А зачем ты
call then to say
звонил тогда чтобы е что-то сказать
something  something just
чтобы что-то просто
said, a random sentence generator
сказа генератор случайных предложений
was imprisoned, they said, Everyone should call.
посадили сказали Каждый должен позвонить
Well, why did you call
Да ну а для чего ты звонил на линию
Putin’s line, what was it? So that it was
Путина что было Чтоб что чтоб
n’t allowed into heaven, it’s called, but
было в рай не пускает называется а
call now, that’s interesting. It’s
позвони сейчас вот интересно Она же
24/7,
круглосуточная
I’m afraid. Well,  ask, ask
на надо я боюсь Ну спроси вот спроси
when demobilization is planned for those
когда планируется Демобилизация для тех
you You have a dad who has been in the war for two years,
ты У тебя папа д второго года на войне
you are helping there ask Well, really,
ты там помогаешь спроси Ну реально Вот
I’m interested, call me, what will they
мне интересно вот Позвони что там сейчас
say at the moment, I’m afraid there
скажут на данный момент я боюсь там
then, that is, there was still all the work in the
тогда то есть ещё было всё работа в
sense of you’re afraid to call
смысле боишься позвонить на горячую
hotline It’s for people to call
линию Она же для того чтобы люди звонили
Nuno I’m afraid Why are you afraid of what could
нуно Я боюсь А чего боишься что может
happen What could happen if you
случиться Что может случиться если ты
call the
позвонишь на горячую
hotline a lot of things, for example, I don’t know Well,
линию много чего например не знаю Ну
the meteorite will suit your dad in short
метеорит у пойдёт твоему папу короче
they'll take you to prison or
заберут В тюрьму или что
what, suppose a meteorite falls The end of the
что предположим метеорит упадёт Корец
world will be
света будет
afraid, that is, I correctly understood that
боишься то есть я правильно понял что
uh, call the hotline It's scary to call
ээ на горячую линию Позвонить страшно
now at the moment yes
теперь на данный момент да А почему
Why why is there such a situation now that at
почему сейчас такая ситуация что на
the moment calling the
данный момент позвонить на горячую линию
president's hotline it could be like-  it’s scary
президента это может быть как-то страшно
Why is it
Почему
interesting because I’m
интересно потому что я
not once again that’s not the point, like
не ещё раз не в том не в том дело типа
explain it Explain why it’s scary
вот объясни Объясни почему страшно
to call the president’s line You, then,
звонить на линию президента Ты же тогда
you called
ты же звонил уже
before I
раньше Я же вам
told you it wasn’t actually me who called, but who’s mom
сказал звонил фактически не я а кто мама
who what  there he said And what were you doing? I
кто что там говорил А ты что делал Я
tried to guess what to tell my mom.
пытался маме предположить что ей сказать
So mom said it or did you say mom
Так мама говорила или ты говорил мама
and who else? In short, okay, I thought you called. Okay, it’s
а кто ещё Короче ладно я думал ты звонил
good what your dad says,
Ладно хорошо что твой папа говорит
by the way, they’re not tired of fighting
кстати не устали они воевать
already, well, whoever’s in the front line is
уже ну кто на передке тот
tired And who’s the artilleryman  they get tired and
устал А кто артиллерист они устают и
sometimes rest And who in general is in the
иногда отдыхают А кто вообще В
rear? Well, your dad is a rear man, as I understand it.
тылу Ну твой папа тыловик я так понимаю
Yes, from the
Да с че
Dans. Well, from these, from the Koreans, no, otherwise I would
данов Ну с этих с корейских нет а то я
think that now they speak Korean in your
думал бы сейчас говорят корейский у вас
place. It’s cool, and what region was he in?
там пово Прикольно а он В какой области
Was and is the Kherson
был Был и находится Херсонская
Kherson region Yes, I understood there from the bird
Херсонская область Да понял там от птахи
to the madra soon they
в мадра скоро ему
tell him I think it will fly to you faster,
говорят Мне кажется к вам быстрее
not I’m far away in California,
прилетит не я далеко я в Калифорнии
but here’s the question: If your dad and he,
а вот вопрос Если твоему папе и он
for example,
например
leaves for what will he
отойдёт ради чего он
get out of it, no one will go anywhere even
получится никто никуда не отойдёт даже
such a thought will never  Well, look, it’s
такой мысли никогда не бы ну смотри Это
war, you can’t guess, today there’s no
война война тут не угадаешь сегодня нет
thought, and tomorrow there’s a funeral, yes
мысли а завтра пришла похоронка да
Question That’s what he’s for.
Вопрос Вот за что
War is war,
он Война войной
but he’s already been through the second war, he’s
но он прошёл уже вот вторую войну
going through the same thing as his grandfather, great-grandfather. Okay, the second one.
проходит как и дед прадед Ладно вторую А
what was the first Chechen war he passed through? And he is
какую первую он прошёл чеченскую А он
still an occupier of people in Chechnya,
ещё в Чечне людей
everyone who is in the war says yes, I
оккупант все кто на войне говорят Да я
passed that one, passed it, and then hop and didn’t pass
прошёл ту прошёл а тут хоп и не прошёл
it because of why this war started,
рате изза чего эта война началась
tell me why this war started because
расскажете из чего эта война началась
you are the Arab people and you
из-за того что вы арабский народ и вас
This king is driving you to slaughter for the sake of his
ваш этот царь гонит на убой ради своих
personal ambitions and interests, and
личных амбиций интересов а вы вместо
instead of asking him the question why
того чтобы задать ему вопрос почему мы
should we die instead of living
должны умирать вместо того чтобы жить
richly in the richest country? Yes, you go
богато в богатейшей стране Да вы идёте
How
Как
some people also help their relatives with their own hands,
какие-то ещё и своими руками помогаете
but you didn’t guess, but
родственникам вот не угадали а Ну
tell me your version
расскажи свою версию
of when Ukraine decided to return something there,
го когда Украина решила что-то там
as I understand it,
вернуть как я понял
Crimea, something is out of the question, stop stop
Крым что-то там уних с кры стоп стоп
stop, you didn’t understand, not Ukraine decided to
стоп ты не понял не Украина решила
return Crimea, but  Russia attacked Crimea and
вернуть Крым а Россия напала на Крым и с
this began the war referendum There was
этого началась война референдум Там те
no referendum on the night of
не какой референдум в ночь с 26 на 27
February 26-27, but I remember that I lived in Crimea I
февраля но я ж помню это я жил в Крыму Я
lived in Crimea No  there was no referendum,
жил в Крыму Не было никакого референдума
Russian troops entered And then they already
зашли российские войска А дальше уже
held some kind of fake referendum,
провели какой-то фейковый референдум
everything Look, I’m asking you, I’m
всё Смотри я тебя спрашиваю
talking about the war Putin started the war in
го говорю про войну Путин начал войну в
14, he captured the Crimea, he captured Donetsk
14м году захватил Крым захватил Донецк
Lugansk, that’s all this, that is, I’ll return this Crimea
Луганск вот это вот всё то есть сй Крым
That is, what do they have there  -look
верну То есть у них там что-то смотри
again Crimea was captured by Russia
ещё раз Крым был захвачен Россией
Subscribe to th Instagram I don’t know
Отпишись на й Instagram Я не знаю для
what this is for  Why else should you be surprised
чого це тоб для чого ще тоб там дивитись
at your face? Ale for you, one two
на оце й фейс Але для тебе це один два
or three clicks Ale you trime me and I
або три клика Але ты тримае мене и я
will be KTA in me there Kupa fouls and in me there
буду КТА в мене там Купа фолов и в мене
will be a cool mood so work robiti Novi
буде класный настрой щоб робити Нови
cool video Write to my Instagram Popik
крут видео Пиши на мий Instagram Попик
Andriy
Андрий
otak Come on  I'm
отак Давай я тебя
checking for you L
чекаю L